So far in this lesson on technical language technical descriptions we've talked about things in sequence
到目前为止，在关于技术语言技术描述的这节课中，我们已经按顺序讨论了一些事情
and dates.
和日期。
Now we're going to focus on symbols not every symbol.
现在我们将关注符号而不是每个符号。
There are billions of symbols.
有数十亿个符号。
We're going to talk about the common symbols that you find on your keyboard.
我们将讨论您在键盘上找到的常见符号。
And we're not going to talk about every one but we're going to talk about the ones that you come across
我们不会谈论每一个，但我们会谈论你遇到的那些
relatively often when we need to say them.
当我们需要说它们时，相对经常。
And when we don't need to say them this is one of the more confusing things that I find a lot of English
当我们不需要说它们时，这是我发现很多英语的更令人困惑的事情之一
learners come across.
学习者遇到。
Should I say this or not.
我应该说还是不说。
Is this symbol here as just a mark to let me know or to organize something so that I kind of know what's
这个符号在这里只是一个让我知道或组织一些东西的标记，以便我知道什么是
going on or do I actually need to speak something here.
继续还是我真的需要在这里说点什么。
How do I know.
我怎么知道。
Well we can go through some of these things.
好吧，我们可以通过其中一些事情。
OK.
好的。
I mean obviously you know at the end of a sentence you have this thing and it's called the period and
我的意思是很明显你知道在句末你有这个东西，它叫做句号和
you don't say period.
你不说期间。
You don't say Mary had a cat named Bob period unless you're dictating nowadays.
除非你现在口述，否则你不会说玛丽有一只名叫鲍勃的猫。
You can use your phone or your computer or whatever to speak and many kinds of software at the moment
你现在可以用你的手机或电脑或任何东西说话和多种软件
require you to say period when you want to end the sentence.
要求您在要结束句子时说出句号。
So yes usually you don't need to but recently you need to more often.
所以是的，通常你不需要，但最近你需要更频繁。
I often use dictation with my phone and I speak and I say Mary had a cat period.
我经常用我的手机听写，我说玛丽有猫时期。 她的猫是黄色时期，它写下了我去那里的时期，我猜我在尝试什么
to say is there are always some cases when you need to be able to actually say all of these otherwise
说是总有一些情况下你需要能够真正说出所有这些，否则
useless.
无用。
All right.
好的。
This symbol it's called a percent.
这个符号叫做百分比。
Think you know it 70 percent of people living in love of love.
想想你知道它 70% 的人生活在爱的爱中。
OK.
好的。
This is a percent symbol percent symbol and it is almost always actually said when written almost always
这是一个百分号百分号，几乎总是在写的时候实际说出来
actually said when written.
实际写的时候说。
Sometimes you might see it just as a visual reference but usually when you come across it you should
有时您可能会将其视为视觉参考，但通常当您遇到它时，您应该
read it.
阅读。
OK.
好的。
We could say maybe a zero point two percent interest rate.
我们可以说可能是零点 2% 的利率。
There will be some cases when you might see it in front of the number but you should still say zero
在某些情况下，您可能会在数字前面看到它，但您仍然应该说零
point two percent.
点百分之二。
So one of the difficult things when you're reading out some technical language is you'll see symbols
因此，当您阅读一些技术语言时，困难之一就是您会看到符号
in different places and what you say is actually not the order that you're reading it in.
在不同的地方，你所说的实际上不是你阅读的顺序。
So you're reading percent zero point two sometimes you're saying zero point two percent.
所以你读的是百分之零点二有时你说的是百分之零点二。
It's the same for for example the dollar sign.
例如美元符号也是如此。
This is called a dollar sign.
这称为美元符号。
And I'm sure you already know that.
我相信你已经知道了。
So we don't really need to focus on it in this lesson.
所以我们真的不需要在本课中关注它。
But you would see something like that.
但是你会看到类似的东西。
You don't say dollar five and you don't say dollar sign five you say five dollars.
你不说五美元，你不说五美元，你说五美元。
So in many cases four different symbols you will have to read things out loud differently than your
所以在很多情况下，四个不同的符号，你将不得不以不同的方式大声读出来。
eyes actually see them.
眼睛居然看到了他们。
All right.
好的。
Let's go on to this one.
让我们继续这个。
This one can be called a no sign a hash or pound.
这个可以称为无符号哈希或磅。
When is it used for each of these.
什么时候用于这些中的每一个。
So the number sign is generally not spoken.
所以一般不说数字符号。
OK if it's spoken you would just say no you won't say no sign I'll just say no.
好的，如果它被说出来，你只会说不，你不会说没有迹象，我只会说不。
So if you see this written down somewhere things in order maybe you're calling out names number seven.
因此，如果您在某处看到按顺序记录下来的内容，那么您可能正在呼唤第七个名字。
Who's number seven.
谁是七号。
Number seven here.
七号在这里。
OK.
好的。
So you would say just.
所以你会说只是。
Number seven.
七号。
Number five hundred fifty three maybe.
可能是五百五十三号。
I don't know maybe there is some sort of drawing and there's a random number in a bucket and you take
我不知道也许有某种图画，桶里有一个随机数，你拿
one out number 62 which is number 60 to see here number 60 to say no.
一个出数字 62 也就是数字 60 看到这里数字 60 说不。
OK.
好的。
Generally it's there to just reference the number and we don't say this part.
一般来说，它只是参考数字，我们不说这部分。
OK hash it's also called the hash.
OK hash 也叫散列。
This started to become much more popular recently in the last I don't know maybe ten years because it's
最近这开始变得越来越流行，我不知道可能是十年，因为它是
part of another word which is hash tag on social media.
另一个词的一部分，它是社交媒体上的哈希标签。
It's a G on social media Twitter wave for Facebook.
这是 Facebook 的社交媒体 Twitter 浪潮中的一个 G。
Facebook is Facebook have hashtags.
Facebook 是 Facebook 有标签。
I think so you see hashtags to let you know what's going on with the post that's been that's been shared
我想你会看到主题标签，让你知道已经分享的帖子发生了什么
on your your home feed or whatever or what it's related to.
在您的家庭供稿上或与之相关的任何内容上。
You can search for other posts that have the same idea or they're related to the same topic.
您可以搜索具有相同想法或与同一主题相关的其他帖子。
It's called the hash tag.
它被称为哈希标签。
So when I'm recording this Instagram is quite popular.
所以当我录制这个 Instagram 时，它很受欢迎。
That of course always changes from year to year.
当然，这总是每年都在变化。
But let's say there's a hash tag insta insta good I think is the number one hashtag.
但是，假设有一个主题标签 insta insta good 我认为是排名第一的主题标签。
I'm not even sure what it means to be honest with you or hash tag.
我什至不确定对你诚实或哈希标签意味着什么。
I can make my own if I write my name here where you make where you post things on Instagram if it's
如果我在这里写下我的名字，我可以自己做
still there.
还在那里。
Hashtag Luke pretty you say the word hashtag.
标签卢克漂亮你说的标签这个词。
OK so that's become much more popular recently.
好的，所以最近变得更流行了。
Pound is something that you hear on the phone.
英镑是您在电话中听到的声音。
If you get an automated message on the phone they'll say please press pound once you're finished with
如果您在电话上收到一条自动消息，他们会说请在您完成后按磅
your recording or when you're finished with your recording please press pound.
您的录音或完成录音后，请按磅。
So you'll see that symbol on the phone.
所以你会在手机上看到那个符号。
And you push it if you'd like to speak with an operator please press pound.
如果您想与接线员交谈，请按磅。
So you hear that often in a recorded message.
因此，您经常在录制的信息中听到这一点。
So generally you won't need to say pound you might often more often say hashtag.
所以通常你不需要说磅，你可能更经常说标签。
And sometimes you might need to say no but not no sign.
有时你可能需要说不，但不是没有迹象。
Now the next one is very common and sometimes it's said sometimes it's not said minus sign is just like
现在下一个很常见，有时说有时不说，减号就像
no sign.
没有迹象。
We don't say sign but we do say minus and we'll talk more about it when we're talking about math problems.
我们不说符号，但我们说减号，当我们谈论数学问题时，我们会更多地谈论它。
But we would say for example seven minus seven seven minus seven.
但是我们会说例如七减七七减七。
Or sometimes we'll say I'll have tomatoes and onions minus cucumber minus cucumber.
或者有时我们会说我要西红柿和洋葱减去黄瓜减去黄瓜。
That means please take away the cucumber.
这意味着请把黄瓜拿走。
Now sometimes it's a dash.
现在有时它是一个破折号。
And if it's written in a number not for an equation not for a math problem but in a number like in an
如果它是用一个数字写的，不是为了一个方程而不是一个数学问题，而是一个数字，比如
email address for example or maybe a user name then you will say dash dash dash OK.
例如电子邮件地址或用户名，然后您会说 dash dash dash OK。
And you actually should speak dash for phone numbers don't actually say it.
你实际上应该说破折号，因为电话号码实际上并没有说出来。
The best way to think of it is if you need to take action on that and actually input it actually input
考虑它的最好方法是，如果您需要对此采取行动并实际输入实际输入
input that then you should say it.
输入，然后你应该说出来。
For example if you're typing out someone's user name to find them then OK say dash B maybe a dash VBA
例如，如果您要输入某人的用户名来查找他们，那么可以说破折号 B 可能是破折号 VBA
whatever it is.
不管是什么。
OK.
好的。
Phone numbers not don't say dash because if it's a phone number it's just there to separate the numbers
电话号码不要说破折号，因为如果它是电话号码，它只是用来分隔数字
and you don't actually put that into the phone.
而你实际上并没有把它放到手机里。
So don't say it.
所以不说了。
OK.
好的。
Hyphens are four words for example.
例如，连字符是四个单词。
Thirty two.
三十二.
We don't say 30 hyphen two but when we're talking about words when we're talking about sentences then
我们不会说 30 个连字符两个，但是当我们谈论单词时，当我们谈论句子时
we use hyphen is there a hyphen between 30 and 2.
我们使用连字符 30 到 2 之间是否有连字符。
Yes there is.
就在这里。
There is a hyphen between 30 and 2.
30 到 2 之间有一个连字符。
OK.
好的。
So we can use the word hyphen to describe this thing between words but we don't actually speak the word
所以我们可以在单词之间使用连字符来描述这个东西，但我们实际上并没有说出这个词
hyphen when we're reading out a sentence.
当我们读出一个句子时，连字符。
Never never never.
从来没有从来没有。
We only use the word hyphen to describe what that is between words.
我们只使用连字符来描述单词之间的内容。
OK.
好的。
So minus sign for math minus to take something away but we don't say sine dash for things like email
所以数学减号的减号可以带走一些东西，但我们不会说正弦破折号用于电子邮件之类的东西
addresses user names but not phone numbers and hyphen.
地址是用户名，但不是电话号码和连字符。
But we don't say it it's just a name for what we see.
但我们并没有说它只是我们所见事物的名称。
If there's this symbol between words like this one.
如果像这样的单词之间有这个符号。
OK.
好的。
I realize I've killed my s h here.
我意识到我已经杀了我的 s h 在这里。
So let me fix that.
所以让我解决这个问题。
There we are.
我们在那里。
Sorry sir.
对不起先生。
OK.
好的。
So let's talk about underscore underscore we pretty much always say underscore when we see it sometimes
所以让我们来谈谈下划线下划线我们几乎总是说下划线，当我们有时看到它时
it might be in a user name sometimes in an email address but because you actually need to put it in
它有时可能在电子邮件地址中的用户名中，但因为您实际上需要将其放入
to input it and if you don't it will be wrong.
输入它，如果你不输入它会是错误的。
You'll find the wrong person then it has to be said Steve underscore Steve at blah blah blah.
你会找到错误的人，然后必须说史蒂夫在等等等等中强调史蒂夫。
Dot com that is maybe an email address.
. com 可能是一个电子邮件地址。
So we should say it.
所以我们应该说。
We should say it the next one is parentheses.
我们应该说下一个是括号。
These are always pretty much always go together.
这些总是几乎总是在一起。
You don't see one alone.
你一个人也看不到。
You don't see just this one or this one.
你不会只看到这个或这个。
So we pretty much always say parentheses will say the word parentheses first and then say the thing
所以我们几乎总是说括号会先说括号这个词，然后说事情
inside of it.
在里面。
Now sometimes we will just say Alex co-founder Alex co-founder that's his role or his.
现在有时我们只会说亚历克斯联合创始人亚历克斯联合创始人那是他的角色或他的角色。
What he does in this company maybe this is at the end of an email.
他在这家公司所做的事情可能是在一封电子邮件的末尾。
Alex co-founder if if we want to make sure people know maybe we're on the phone that this is within
亚历克斯联合创始人如果我们想确保人们知道也许我们在电话里说这是在
parentheses maybe it's in a sentence you can say Alex parentheses co-founder Alex parentheses co-founder.
括号也许它在一个句子中你可以说亚历克斯括号联合创始人亚历克斯括号联合创始人。
OK so that's when we would actually say parentheses or if we're going to describe it you could say oh
好的，那时我们实际上会说括号，或者如果我们要描述它，你可以说哦
it's by the way co-founder is in parentheses co-founder is in Peru sees if it's a phone number though
顺便说一下 联合创始人在括号里 联合创始人在秘鲁 看看是不是电话号码
we don't say it.
我们不说。
So if you see Parentheses in a phone number never say it because why not.
因此，如果您在电话号码中看到括号，请不要说出来，因为为什么不呢。
Because when you're putting in the number you don't actually put that in you don't input it.
因为当您输入数字时，您实际上并没有输入数字。
So usually we don't need to say it because most of the time it's in that sort of situation.
所以通常我们不需要说出来，因为大多数时候它都是在那种情况下。
Often we don't need to actually say parentheses because it just tells us a little bit of extra information.
通常我们不需要真正说出括号，因为它只是告诉我们一些额外的信息。
So only if it's necessary to know that it is inside of parentheses.
所以只有当有必要知道它在括号内时。
Do we actually say it.
我们真的这么说吗。
And sometimes we can make the decision whether or not to say it based on whether or not we feel it's
有时我们可以根据我们是否感觉到它来决定是否说它
important for people to know who are listening that it is inside parentheses.
重要的是人们知道谁在听，它在括号内。
So quotes or quotation marks often tell us that something was said.
所以引号或引号经常告诉我们说了什么。
And so when we're reading something out we don't have to say quotation mark because it is.
因此，当我们阅读某些内容时，我们不必说引号，因为它是。
So we're just saying what that person said.
所以我们只是说那个人说的话。
She said I can't I can't.
她说我不行我不行。
But sometimes maybe if she said isn't there and I just want to say I can't.
但有时如果她说不在那里，我只想说我不能。
And I want to make sure you know that it's something someone said and I'm not saying it.
我想确保你知道这是某人说的，而我没有说。
Then I have to say by the way that's in quotes that's in quotes that's in quotation marks.
然后我不得不说引号中的引号中的引号中的方式。
Usually we'll say quotes.
通常我们会说引号。
So by the way I can't it's not what I'm saying.
所以顺便说一句，我不能这不是我要说的。
It's in quotes.
它在引号中。
So we won't actually say quotation mark.
所以我们实际上不会说引号。
I can't.
我不能。
Quotation mark.
引号。
No.
不。
We'll say I can't.
我们会说我不能。
That's in quotes or quote I can't quote I can't say we'll say either quote I can't or that's in quotation
那是引号或引号我不能引用我不能说我们会说我不能或者那是引用
marks or that's in quotations or that's in quotes.
标记或在引号中或在引号中。
This one as I mentioned is air quotes.
正如我所提到的，这是空中报价。
If someone is looking at you she said I can't I can't I'm telling you that I'm not saying my own words.
如果有人看着你，她说我不能，我不能我告诉你，我不是在说我自己的话。
I'm saying someone else's words.
我在说别人的话。
And it's a way to sort of mark that forward slash and backslash almost always said because usually it's
这是一种标记正斜杠和反斜杠几乎总是说的方式，因为通常它是
in a you are L most of the time when you see these it's in a U.R.L. you need to be able to type that
大多数情况下，当你看到这些时，它是在 U.R.L.你需要能够输入
in when you're when you're putting in the U.R.L..
当你把 U.R.L. 放进去的时候。
So we'll say forward slash backslash.
所以我们会说正斜杠反斜杠。
Sometimes it's just set as Slash if it's in a sentence for example.
例如，有时它只是设置为 Slash，如果它在一个句子中。
And there are two options.
并且有两种选择。
For example you could have a banana or Apple and it's telling you that you can choose a banana slash
例如，你可以有一个香蕉或苹果，它告诉你你可以选择香蕉斜线
apple banana slash Apple OK or sometimes you could say banana or apple banana or Apple.
apple 香蕉斜线 Apple OK 或者有时你可以说香蕉或苹果香蕉或苹果。
OK so you could say or there or you could say slash there if it's in a U R L it's very very important
好的，所以你可以说 or there 或者你可以说 slash where 如果它在 U R L 中，这是非常非常重要的
to make sure to say this one or this one because forward slash goes this way and backslash goes that
确保说这个或这个，因为正斜杠是这样，反斜杠是这样
way.
方法。
So it's very important to say which one you're talking about.
所以说你在说哪一个是非常重要的。
Comma is pretty much never said it's only said to describe what this thing is.
逗号几乎从未说过它只是用来描述这个东西是什么。
This thing is called a comma.
这个东西叫做逗号。
This is a comma.
这是一个逗号。
If you're doing dictation like I mentioned before then you might actually say comma I said comma that.
如果您像我之前提到的那样进行听写，那么您实际上可能会说逗号，我说的是逗号。
OK but most of the time you do not need to actually say it when you read it.
好的，但大多数时候你不需要在阅读时实际说出来。
Ninety nine point nine nine percent unless you are dictating what about Colon.
百分之九十九点九九分，除非你在口述结肠的情况。
What about Colon if you remember in our email class we used a colon to create a list.
如果您还记得在我们的电子邮件课程中我们使用冒号创建列表，那么冒号怎么样。
It's called a colon colon and we used it to create one 2 three things or two things I think it was that
它被称为冒号，我们用它来创建一两三件事或两件事我认为是
needed to be done a request.
需要完成一个请求。
So we'll often say please do the following then we'll write a colon then we'll say 1 2 and 3.
所以我们经常说请执行以下操作，然后我们会写一个冒号，然后我们会说 1 2 和 3。
So usually you do not need to say colon colon unless you're describing something like what you're doing.
所以通常你不需要说冒号，除非你描述的是你正在做的事情。
And then I wrote colon 1 2 3.
然后我写了冒号 1 2 3。
But if you're actually just reading for example that email that we read in the class about writing emails
但是，如果您实际上只是在阅读例如我们在课堂上阅读的有关编写电子邮件的电子邮件
you do not need to say colon.
你不需要说冒号。
So this is very similar to comma and in fact semicolon is the same way most of the time you do not need
所以这与逗号非常相似，实际上分号在大多数情况下都不需要
to read out semicolon unless you're describing what you're doing.
读出分号，除非你在描述你在做什么。
You need a semicolon here.
这里需要一个分号。
I think if you put a semicolon there then the whole sentence will make more sense.
我认为如果你在那里放一个分号，那么整个句子会更有意义。
Oh yeah.
哦耶。
Good idea.
好主意。
So you need to know these things like commas colons periods to help other people maybe with their grammar
所以你需要知道这些东西，比如逗号冒号，以帮助其他人了解他们的语法
with their sentences.
用他们的句子。
Otherwise you don't need to actually say them an asterisk is usually used to reference or mentions something
否则，您不需要实际说出它们，星号通常用于引用或提及某些内容
below.
以下。
Maybe this is beside a name or a statement about a product on a box and then at the bottom you need
也许这是在盒子上关于产品的名称或声明旁边，然后在您需要的底部
to read more details about that.
阅读有关此的更多详细信息。
So if you see an asterisk you don't need to say asterisk.
因此，如果您看到星号，则无需说星号。
You just look at the bottom of the box.
你只要看在盒子的底部。
So in that way it's kind of similar to these where you really only need to say it.
所以在这种情况下，它有点类似于这些你真的只需要说出来的地方。
If you're talking about that thing or you really need to say oh there's an asterisk there I wonder what
如果您在谈论那件事，或者您真的需要说哦，那里有一个星号，我想知道什么
it says at the bottom of the page or at the bottom of the box star then is used on a phone if it's on
它显示在页面底部或框星的底部，然后在手机上使用（如果它处于开启状态）
a phone it's called a star if it's on a page a product a box.
一部手机，如果它在一个页面上，一个产品，一个盒子，它就被称为明星。
It's called an asterisk.
它被称为星号。
OK.
好的。
Sometimes you need to say you need to press star you need to press star.
有时您需要说您需要按星号，您需要按星号。
Usually not.
通常不会。
Not many things require you to push the star key but sometimes right.
没有多少事情需要你按下星键，但有时是正确的。
Sometimes on a computer keyboard it's an asterisk on a phone.
有时在电脑键盘上它是手机上的星号。
It's a star.
这是一颗星星。
That's a simple way to remember it.
这是一种简单的记忆方式。
All right.
好的。
Well how about this one the old classic period that we talked about at the beginning of our symbols
好吧，我们在符号开始时谈到的那个古老的经典时期怎么样
discussion.
讨论。
Well it's called a dot.
好吧，它被称为点。
It's called a period and it's called a point just like comma colon semicolon an asterisk.
它被称为句号，它被称为点，就像逗号冒号分号和星号一样。
We typically don't need to and also hyphen we typically don't need to say this when we read it period.
我们通常不需要，也不需要连字符，当我们阅读它时，我们通常不需要说这个。
But as I mentioned earlier if you're dictating you do or if you're making a clear point about something
但正如我之前提到的，如果你是在口授，或者你是在对某事提出明确的观点
and you want to focus on the fact that there's no way around it.
你想专注于没有办法绕过它的事实。
I'm going tomorrow.
我明天去。
I don't care if it rains.
我不在乎是否下雨。
I don't care if you say no I am going period.
我不在乎你是否说不，我要来月经了。
The meaning of that period if I say it is there's no other option.
那个时期的意义如果我说是没有别的选择。
There's no alternative.
没有其他选择。
I am very very clear about my opinion and nobody can tell me not to.
我非常清楚我的意见，没有人可以告诉我不要这样做。
Nothing can stop me usually.
通常没有什么能阻止我。
So it's very certain.
所以非常确定。
This is the end period.
这是结束时期。
Oh it's usually very serious.
哦，通常很严重。
OK.
好的。
Dot would be for things like email addresses so we can consider this one more like e-mail or a U.R.L.
点将用于电子邮件地址之类的东西，因此我们可以将其视为更像电子邮件或 U.R.L.
Web site.
网站。
We always say dot com and a point for a number.
我们总是说 dot com 和一个数字点。
So for example zero point three or six point two or seven point one so point four numbers period four
所以例如零点三或六点二或七点一所以点四数字周期四
sentences and dot for you are L's e-mails and things like that.
给你的句子和点是 L 的电子邮件之类的东西。
Hopefully you're clear on these symbols.
希望您清楚这些符号。
There are lots of others certainly but at least you should have an idea about when you can use these
当然还有很多其他的，但至少你应该知道什么时候可以使用这些
when you should say them when you shouldn't say them and when they're just meant to describe that thing
什么时候该说，什么时候不该说，什么时候只是为了描述那件事
and you only use it when you're talking about for example a hyphen you need a hyphen there.
并且您仅在谈论例如连字符时才使用它，而那里需要连字符。
I think really yes you need a hyphen there.
我认为真的是的，你需要一个连字符。
Oh OK.
哦好的。
Add a hyphen.
添加连字符。
Now let's go on and actually look at a real example.
现在让我们继续看一个真实的例子。